There we have learned about the premise algorithm that's tried to implement it and see and see how to
write its code.
So we start by defining that fee equal to five.
This is the definition and that infinity nine, 99 and so on.
So created to the array of size five times five for adjacency matrix to represent the class, please
go back to the adjacency matrix in the previous figures in the graph in order to learn more about it.
So this is the adjacency graph I will make it and in the green and.
And here we have it.
OK, so this is the graph, and this is the adjacency matrix, we start by making the main int main
here and we start by making that number of edges, says a variable representing the number of edges
of the graph.
Create a way to track selected vertex selected will be come true, otherwise false.
So this is the selected array.
It has our vertex as its length.
And now it is making the selected vertices is tracking forward if it is selected or not.
So how to make this?
We set the selected falls initially we make of that MEMS test.
This is the method that we will create in the next couple of minutes and we passed the selected.
This is the selected array and falls set everything to false because we have initially at at zero.
We are initially we didn't.
We didn't go to any vertex.
OK.
And we passed the size of that selected no.
The number of edges also siblings led to incidents at the zoo at the initial step.
So the number of edge and minimum spanning tree will be always less than v minus one.
So this is very important less than one than minimum spanning of that tree.
And where is the number of vertices in the graph and which shows there zeros?
The first vertex, which is zero and make it through?
OK.
Now we make index and entwine index represent the wrong number and way to present that column.
No, no.
Let's print for edge and wait, we print print f and we start by printing their atch while number of
edge less than v minus one.
This is the condition that we have represented here.
It is always less than three minus one.
So what we will do, we will make it do X and Y, and we represent and start making it forward.
Look, that test for the number of edges less than v minus one.
So for every vertex in the set s, find that all adjacent vertices and calculate the distance from the
vertex selected at step one.
If the first is a ready in the set s, discard it.
Otherwise, choose another vertex nearest to the selected vertex.
Step one.
So we will create the minimum as infinity.
We set all the more and the the vertices as minimum.
So please go back to the animation in the previous video in order to learn how to set it and why we
are setting this and have the algorithms work for the prince.
We make a for loop.
Nested for the loop, and we start if selected, it's true, if selected at I index is selected, then
go and go and go inside this nested loop.
Nested loops goes from zero to v and the checking if it is not selected at Index J and J at Index II
and the J.
So this is through.
This is not false and this is true and this is not false gain not selected.
So select if it is not selected and there is an edge, then check if minimum greater.
Then at index ie at Index J, then set the minimum index g at index at Index J and Set X equal to I
and tap Y equal to.
This is how we set the things, how we can move from point to point in the prelims algorithm.
Now we print the selected and we print that vertices and the selected by Index Y equal to True said
that through a number of edge increase by one.
So this is how the algorithm works in sea.
So let's go to Java compiler and let's run it and test it in the next event.
So for that, I want from you to write this code in your compiler, into your C compiler and into your
copy book.
And please try to play with the codes and test it and partition that code in order to understand it
for every step and watch again.